<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<gallery>


<image>
    <title>Escape from R'lyeh</title>
    <file>cthulhu.jpg</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
            <p style="text-align:center;font-size:smaller;font-style:italic;">
            If you particularly like this drawing, you can
            <a href="http://www.cafepress.ca/haggholm/7960542">get it on
            a t-shirt</a> via
            <a href="http://www.cafepress.ca/haggholm/7960542">CafePress</a>.
            </p>
            <blockquote>
                 <p>
                 Steam had not been suffered to go down entirely, despite the
                 departure of all hands for the shore; and it was the work of
                 only a few moments of feverish rushing up and down between
                 wheel and engines to get the Alert under way. Slowly, amidst
                 the distorted horrors of that indescribable scene, she began
                 to churn the lethal waters; whilst on the masonry of that
                 charnel shore that was not of earth the titan Thing from the
                 stars slavered and gibbered like Polypheme cursing the fleeing
                 ship of Odysseus. Then, bolder than the storied Cyclops, great
                 Cthulhu slid greasily into the water and began to pursue with
                 vast wave-raising strokes of cosmic potency.
                 </p>
                 <footer>H.P. Lovecraft, <cite title="The Call of Cthulhu">The Call of Cthulhu</cite></footer>
            </blockquote>
            <p>
				An experiment with applying ink with a brush, which I had done
				only once before, and never to detailed work. Details were
				enhanced with pens. My drawing was based, naturally enough, on
				Lovecraft’s description of Cthulhu:
            </p>
            <blockquote>
            	<p>
				A pulpy, tentacled head surmounted a grotesque and scaly body
				with rudimentary wings … It represented a monster of
				vaguely anthropoid outline, but with an octopus-like head whose
				face was a mass of feelers, a scaly, rubbery-looking body,
				prodigious claws on hind and fore feet, and long, narrow wings
				behind. This thing, which seemed instinct with a fearsome and
				unnatural malignancy, was of a somewhat bloated corpulence …
            	</p>
            	<footer>Ibid.</footer>
            </blockquote>
            <p>
            <em>Some</em> of the reasons my Cthulhu looks a bit unlike a lot
            of depictions have to do with paying attention to that: Note
            <q><em>rudimentary</em> wings</q>, for instance, and <q>bloated
            corpulence</q>.
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
        Ink.
    </details>
</image>

<image>
    <title>Arise, demon!</title>
    <file>arise.jpg</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>
                I don’t really have anything to say about this one. Nothing
                beats a little virgin sacrifice in the morning.
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
         0.5 mm mechanical pencil.
    </details>
</image>

<image>
    <title>Futility</title>
    <file>futility.png</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>
                I think the title says it all. The scan quality is not the
                best; some of the finer details (such as the teeth) don’t
                show up well or at all, but I'm reasonably happy with the
                image in general.
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
        Ink pens over mechanical pencil sketch.
    </details>
</image>

<image>
    <title>Dread Sentry</title>
    <file>dread_sentry.jpg</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>
                The Dread Sentry is vaguely inspired by a death knight in a
                planned RPG campaign of my own design (that may or may not ever
                get off the ground). It was drawn in two classes; sketched in
                one and fleshed out in another. Unfortunately, it does not at
                all portray the power of the death knight whom I had in
                mind—nevertheless, as a picture, I am reasonably content with
                it.
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
        0.5 mm mechanical pencil.
    </details>
</image>

<image>
    <title>Black Magic</title>
    <file>wizard.png</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>
                A dark wizard hard at work; I'm not sure what he’s brewing, but
                I’m reasonably certain it's both more potent and more malicious
                than your average witch’s brew.
            </p>
            <p>
            	This picture was drawn as a (very belated) Christmas gift for
            	my good friend <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/sheepeeh">Sheepy</a>,
            	who is in possession of the original (and who scanned it for
            	me after my scan mysteriously disappeared), for which reason I
            	put more effort into the details than I normally do (though
            	unfortunately, many of those details are somewhat too small
            	to show up well at this resolution). She requested something
            	representative of what I like to draw:
            	<q>Goblins and eyeballs and stuff</q>—voilà!
            </p>
            <p>
                Other than a horrible mistake in inking, mostly covered up
                (but still present and as you see it), I'm rather pleased with
                it. Ah, and incidentally, the imp and cherub are the classical
                cartoon representations of the wizard’s conscience.
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
        Ink pens over mechanical pencil sketch.
    </details>
</image>

<image>
    <title>The Fury of Stormwing</title>
    <file>dragonfury.png</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>
                Tormented by unsatiable hunger and burning with the fire that
                was in him, raving and ravenous, Stormwing, greatest of all
                the flying dragons in their first Age, went on a rampage,
                razing cities and burning or devouring every living thing in
                his path. Ultimately, it took the concerted efforts of the
                Dragonlord and the one who would much later become greatest of
                the Dragonlords to slay the beast.
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
        Ink pens (mechanical pencil sketch, since erased).
    </details>
</image>

<image>
    <title>Doom</title>
    <file>devil.jpg</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>
                A doodle I did on a bus and refined whilst waiting for a ferry;
                quick work and fairly small, but I’m quite pleased with it.
                To me there appears to be a certain power in him—but I find
                this power easier to represent in this image than in words, so
                I shall be less long-winded here than is customary for me.
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
        0.5 mm mechanical pencil.
    </details>
</image>

<image>
    <title>Barbarian Warrior</title>
    <file>warrior.jpg</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>
                A barbarian warrior, delivering his challenge with posture.
            </p>
            <p>
                This was done during a short break in drawing class (yes, I
                took a basic drawing class). We had just been introduced to
                the basics of gesture drawing, and I felt like applying what
                I percieved to be the central concept to something more free
                and fun, drawn from my head, not life. Nothing fancy; it's
                just an attempt to convey a sense of movement.
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
        Pencil.
    </details>
</image>

<image>
    <title>The Dragon Summoner</title>
    <file>dragon_summoner.jpg</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>
                What few wizards seem to realise is that summoning a servant
                is not the most important part. Mastering the servant is.
            </p>
            <p>
            	This is really the second version of a much (much) older
            	picture. Unfortunately, you cannot compare and contrast the
            	two because the older version is also much too poor for me
            	to display here without feeling embarrassed.
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
        0.7 mm and 0.3 mm mechanical pencils.
    </details>
</image>

<image>
    <title>Evil Goblin</title>
    <file>evil_goblin_2.jpg</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
            <p class="c">
                One of many renditions of my favourite random Evil Goblin&trade;.
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
        Mechanical pencil.
    </details>
</image>

<image>
    <title>Freedom!</title>
    <file>golem.jpg</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>
                A Golem, Demon or God of the Earth—I don't know which—breaks
                free after eons of being trapped within the cold darkness of
                the bedrock. With a force that can tear mountains asunder and
                the pain of stone torn apart, it surfaces at last to walk the
                world anew—but to what purpose, I cannot say.
            </p>
            <p>
                While it’s obviously a rough drawing, drawn with a much softer
                pencil than I’m prone to use, I'm quite pleased with this as
                an anatomical study—please tell me what’s wrong with it if you
                find anything, but bear in mind that it was done entirely
                without reference, although Lori helped me by pointing out a
                mistake (now fixed) I made with the pectoral muscles. I'm also
                fairly pleased with the dynamics—for once I'm fairly sure that
                he looks like he’s moving…
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
        Soft-lead pencil.
    </details>
</image>

<image>
    <title>The Duel</title>
    <file>hammerduel.jpg</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
            <p class="c">
                David vs. Goliath’s bigger, badder brother? My money's on the big guy.
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
        Pencils.
    </details>
</image>

<image>
    <title>The First Harbinger</title>
    <file>harbinger.jpg</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
        	<blockquote>
				<p>
					It stood by the dead tree, turning its head this way and
					that, then entered the clearing. … Pale light glinted
					now and then from its eyes, but although their cover was
					imperfect it seemed not to notice them. There was a
					frightening intelligence in its eyes…sharp and
					bright and filled with a palpable malevolence.
				</p>
				<p>
					It appeared to be unarmed, though it was difficult to tell;
					it could easily be hiding an entire arsenal of knives and guns
					among the black rags and tatters of its garments. Only the
					hood was in marginally good shape, frayed around the edges
					but whole enough to conceal most of the Harbinger’s
					features. He could see a flash of pale skin, though; its
					chin, open to the light, was a deathly white, as were its
					thin lips. Finally giving up it hissed softly, flashing a
					set of white fangs, and stalked off in the brush.
        		</p>
        	</blockquote>

            <p>
                Omen, the First Harbinger, is one of the most mysterious and
                resourceful servants of the sorcerer Nekros, a product of
                the Necromancer’s twisted magic. An undead creature possessed
                of both unnatural strength and a wicked cunning he hunts
                down relentlessly both those who oppose his master and those
                who fail him.
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
        Ink pens over mechanical pencil sketch.
    </details>
</image>

<image>
    <title>The Dragonlord</title>
    <file>dragonlord.jpg</file>
    <caption>
        <![CDATA[
            <p>
                The Dragonlord, leaning against a wall after a battle, tired
                not in the body but in the spirit after centuries of fighting
                and killing. If you think I drew him with the face turned away
                just so I wouldn't have to draw it, you’re right (I tried, I
                failed), but I rather like the result, anyway.
            </p>
        ]]>
    </caption>
    <details>
        Pencil.
    </details>
</image>

</gallery>
